<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- New document created with EditiX at Tue Jun 07 14:21:44 CEST 2011 -->
<req_document xmlns="req_document.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="req_document.xsd req_document.xsd">
<title>Get Real 0.2</title>
<version>1.0</version>

<p id="1">
<title>Introduction</title>

<p id="1.1">
<title>Purpose</title>
<text_body>The software described in this document is the http://getreal.ous.edu website
and associated support pages. Rev1 of the website was created on or about
summer of 2006. This document describes requirements for Rev2, summer of
2007. There may be a need for future updates of the website.
The scope of the Get Real website is limited to attracting and encouraging
Oregon high school students to take coursework leading toward a
baccalaureate degree in computer science (CS) at one of the seven Oregon
University System campuses.</text_body>
</p>
<p id="1.2">
<text_body>There are no standard document requirements for this document.</text_body>
</p>
<p id="1.3">
<title>Intended Audience and Reading Suggestions</title>
<text_body>Primary readers of this document are the web designers contributing to and
testing of the Get Real website.
Contributors to this document are members of the Computer Science Task
Force subcommittee of ETIC.
The remaining sections of this SRS describe the functional requirements for
Get Real site.</text_body>
</p>
<p id="1.4">
<title>Project Scope</title>
<text_body>The scope of the Get Real website is to provide a high school teen friendly set
of web pages that are easy to navigate and at the same time provides
sufficient depth and information about careers in computer science.
Two potential groups of viewers (students) exist: 1) students interested in CS
seeking more in-depth information about a CS career, and 2) college bound
students not necessarily interested in CS who might be attracted to a CS
career with the right “push” from information on the Get Real site.
The goal of Get Real is to encourage more Oregon students to choose
computer science and related majors, eventually increasing the number of
computer science graduates from Oregon universities.
Maintaining a teen friendly site is deemed of highest importance in order to
hold student attention and guide the viewer to information that will lead to a
decision to pursue a career in CS. Benefits for using the site should include:
<itemize>
<item>Personal and Career information from a broad spectrum of CS
professionals</item>
<item>CS course and other information from OUS campuses</item>
<item>Timely and up to date information that encourages readers to return
to the site, may include Q &amp;amp; A</item>
<item>Call to action, and plans for students to follow to prepare for a CS
career</item>
</itemize>
</text_body>
<text_body>Related sites visited by students to gain career information include: Google,
Yahoo, news.myspace.com, engineergirl.org, etc. (need more input from
students and from HS counselors)</text_body>
</p>
<p id="1.5">
<title>References</title>
<text_body>For web page development at the Capital Center, use the local site files for
Dreamweaver on ~cn-capctr/share/Get_Real_website/~
Be cautious of others modifying pages on the site. Always use Dreamweaver
check in/out feature.
Adhere to CSS and other style conventions established in Get Real version 1.

"List any other documents or Web addresses to which this SRS refers. These
may include user interface style guides, contracts, standards, system
requirements specifications, use case documents, or a vision and scope
document. Provide enough information so that the reader could access a copy
of each reference, including title, author, version number, date, and source or
location."</text_body>
</p>
</p>
<p id="2">
<title>Overall Description</title>
<p id="2.1">
<title>Product Perspective</title>
<text_body>This product is an update of the existing Get Real web site version 1. The new
site will be version 2. A future version 3 may be needed to incorporate ideas
learned from version 2.</text_body>
</p>
<p id="2.2">
<title>Produce Features</title>
<text_body>Major features of the Get Real website include the following pages/subsections:
(existing pages/sections)
Exploring College
Jobs &amp;amp; Money
Real People
Women in Computing
Resources
I’m Looking For…
Articles
(proposed new pages/sections, need to prototype and prioritize list)
High School Courses Search for additional information
Professional Organizations
RSS feeds of current CS information
Ask an Engineer, Ask a Prof – FAQ
Consider a CS minor in other professions
Other ideas/page proposals </text_body>
</p>
<p id="2.3">
<title>User Classes and Characteristics</title>
<text_body>Users are typical Oregon high school students, grades 9 to12 in ALL high
schools across Oregon.
Two potential groups of viewers (students) exist:
1) students interested in CS finding more concise information about a CS
career, and
2) college bound students not necessarily interested in CS who might be
attracted to a CS career with the right “push” from information on the
Get Real site.
A third group of students might be those interested careers as diverse as
protein research, weather prediction, neurobotics, medicine, law or other
sciences where a CS minor could contribute to a better understanding of data
and information. A “Consider a CS minor” section could provide helpful
information.
Oregon High school students from several schools and classes were
interviewed to gain their feedback on version 1 of the Get Real site. Common
themes emerged in the need to change/update overall site graphic design and
real people. Students who are not generally interested in CS, suggested graphic
design changes, more white space, pictures, and easier to navigate
pages. This group was much less tolerant of the site than the CS folks
had been. They wanted a site that “spoke to them” and felt that if you
were not a computer science student, it had very little to offer. The
suggestion was very strong that the site be broken into more readable
chunks of information. The term “walls of text” appeared several times.
The need for more visually attractive information also was a central
theme. They wanted color, photos, diagrams, charts, etc. to break up
the text and make the site attractive. Many of them commented
positively on the spinning globe and satellite menu.
Students who are interested in CS and engineering suggested changes in
the Real People, Resources, and Colleges sections. Most of them spent
their time in the college comparison chart, and in the real people part of
the site. It sounded like they were attracted by the pictures. Several
commented positively on the sections in each person’s story. The college
comparison chart again scored positive marks. Changes to version 2 should include design changes to all existing pages to
shorten up paragraphs and add bullets and charts where possible to accommodate faster page reading and shorter reader attention span. One
example used on the engineergirl.org site uses an interactive table menu for
more detailed information, leaving the main pages short and to the point. "Identify the various user classes that you anticipate will use this product.
User classes may be differentiated based on frequency of use, subset of
product functions used, technical expertise, security or privilege levels,
educational level, or experience. Describe the pertinent characteristics of each
user class. Certain requirements may pertain only to certain user classes.
Distinguish the favored user classes from those who are less important to
satisfy."</text_body>
</p>
<p id="2.4">
<title>Operating Environment</title>
<text_body>The Get Real site runs as an extension of the OUS site e.g. ~getreal.ous.edu~
Being part of the OUS domain will maximize Google and other search engine
hits. The site runs on OSU servers.</text_body>
</p>
<p id="2.5">
<title>Design and Implementation Constraints</title>
<text_body>Constraints for the website include:
Space
Bandwidth for video streaming
Limited availability of Chancellor’s Office resources</text_body>
</p>
<p id="2.6">
<title>User Documentation</title>
<text_body>There are no user documents.</text_body>
</p>
<p id="2.7">
<title>Assumptions and Dependencies</title>
<text_body>There are no development assumptions or dependencies.</text_body>
</p>
</p>
<p id="3">
<title>Get Real Pages &amp;amp; Sections</title>
<text_body>This section provides more detailed information about each web page.</text_body>
<p id="3.1">
<title>Exploring College (existing)</title>
<text_body>A listing of the computer science offerings from Oregon university System
campuses and other Oregon colleges.
>Need to determine extent of community and private colleges in Oregon</text_body>
</p>
<p id="3.2">
<title>Jobs &amp; Money (existing)</title>
<text_body>Offers answers to the questions: “how can I contribute to society and how
much money can I make with a computer science degree?”</text_body>
</p>
<p id="3.3">
<title>Real People (existing)</title>
<text_body>A people section outlining recent CS graduates and more experienced
professionals in CS and related careers. A key point is to show real people
using their CS knowledge in diverse fields, and not cooped up in a cubicle.
Students are interested in two groups of professionals, recent grads, and
experienced professionals. The use of video or audio could help convey a
personal message that could “push” some students to pursue a CS degree.
>see examples from UW CS videos</text_body>
<p id="3.3.1">
<title>Example video “real people” profiles</title>
<text_body>Computer science students and young professionals are presented here: “a day
in the life of” “power to change the world” and Pathways in computer science”
http://www.cs.washington.edu/education/ugrad/prospective/download.html
>reviewers of this document should review these videos – click link above then
“Video Downloads Available” These profiles convey clear messages of CS
majors using their degrees in a variety of diverse careers.</text_body>
</p>
</p>
<p id="3.4">
<title>Women in Computer Science (existing with new name)</title>
<text_body>The intent is to profile women computer scientists and engineers as people
who work every day to solve problems and make the world a better, cleaner,
safer place.
“These women are also actively involved in their communities, raising families,
and enjoying all kinds of sports and hobbies.” www.engineergirl.org is an
example of youth oriented site that shows women in exciting engineering
careers and has good use of white space on the pages.</text_body>
<p id="3.4.1">
<title>Other resources for women in computer science</title>
<text_body>WICS UO, www.cs.uoregon.edu/groups/wics/
www.cis.upenn.edu/acg/wicarch.html this site lists a resource for those
wishing to contact women in computer architecture. Get Real might use a
similar list for girls interested in contacting recent grads or women CS
professionals.</text_body>
</p>
</p>
<p id="3.5">
<title>Resources (existing)</title>
<text_body>Explore a wide range of pre-college technology programs and courses for high
school students.</text_body>
</p>
<p id="3.6">
<title>I’m Looking For… (existing)</title>
<text_body>A list of focused questions and answers with links inside the Get Real site.
topics include: money, people, and colleges.</text_body>
</p>
<p id="3.7">
<title>Articles (existing)</title>
<text_body>A list of articles outside the Get Real site including “50 best jobs in America,
Dream Jobs 2007, etc.</text_body>
</p>
<p id="3.8">
<title>High School Courses (new)</title>
<text_body>The intent of this section is to show recommended curricula for high school
students interested in CS and related careers. This page should provide
pointers to curricula recommendations from OUS campuses and other
university sources. The ACM has recommended curricula for HS CS students.
>UO is working on this area, no other campus has recommended HS courses</text_body>
</p>
<p id="3.9">
<title>Search for additional information (new)</title>
<text_body>At least two kinds of searches are needed, 1) internal search of the Get Real
site, and 2) external search of CS related outside sites such as OUS campuses,
articles on CS etc. Google, for example provides tools for internal and external
searches. The Get Real prototype index page
~getreal.ous.edu/protoindex.html has examples of various search engines.</text_body>
</p>
<p id="3.10">
<title>Professional Organizations (new)</title>
<text_body>A listing with links to ACM, IEEE, and key sub groups such as SIGGRAPH, to
show students the national and international strength of CS organizations.
Pointers should lead to student sections of these organizations.</text_body>
</p>
<p id="3.11">
<title>RSS feeds of current CS information (new)</title>
<text_body>Selected articles from the chancellor’s office daily communications distribution,
fed to RSS subscribers on the Get Real site. This feature requires X hours per
week of web design resource for editing the URLs to the DSS feed.</text_body>
</p>
<p id="3.12">
<title>Ask a Grad or Prof – FAQ (new)</title>
<text_body>Get fast feedback from the Oregon University System on questions asked in a
Q and A format. Answers are posted in an FAQ section for all to read. A Grad
or Prof BLOG on CS careers would also work here.</text_body>
</p>
<p id="3.13">
<title>Consider a CS Minor (new)</title>
<text_body>Information for students in medicine, law, business, and other professions to
provide students visibility of the high value of having a CS minor. The video
“pathways in Computer Science” is a good example of CS majors in diverse
fields</text_body>
</p>
<p id="3.14">
<text_body>Other new page ideas here…</text_body>
</p>
</p>
<p id="4">
<title>External Interface Requirements</title>
<p id="4.1">
<title>User Interfaces</title>
<text_body>The Get Real site should work and be tested against IE, Firefox and Netscape.</text_body>
</p>
<p id="4.2">
<title>Hardware Interfaces</title>
<text_body>There are no special hardware interface requirements</text_body>
</p>
<p id="4.3">
<title>Software Interfaces</title>
<text_body>There are no special software interface requirements</text_body>
</p>
<p id="4.4">
<title>Communications Interfaces</title>
<text_body>There are no special communication interface requirements</text_body>
</p>
</p>
<p id="5">
<title>Other Nonfunctional Requirements</title>
<p id="5.1">
<title>Performance Requirements</title>
<text_body>The Get Real site should be hosted on a server that can provide adequate
response time. High school students tend to have short attentions spans, so a
slow server would not be satisfactory for this application. The current OUS
(www.ous.edu) site is a good example of rapid response time.</text_body>
</p>
<p id="5.2">
<title>Security Requirements</title>
<text_body>Copyright and other security measures for Get Real should be the same as the
OUS site.</text_body>
</p>
<p id="5.3">
<text_body>There is a need to track and evaluate the “hits” and time spent on the
student-focused website over time; and make content, design, and navigation
changes as needed based on evaluation of hits.</text_body>
<p id="5.3.1">
<title>Software Quality Attributes</title>
<text_body>Web design conventions should be consistent with the standards and
conventions used on the OUS site. "Specify any additional quality characteristics for the product that will be
important to either the customers or the developers. Some to consider are:
adaptability, availability, correctness, flexibility, interoperability,
maintainability, portability, reliability, reusability, robustness, testability, and
usability. Write these to be specific, quantitative, and verifiable when possible.
At the least, clarify the relative preferences for various attributes, such as ease
of use over ease of learning."</text_body>
</p>
</p>
</p>
<p id="6">
<title>Get Real Version 3 Suggestions</title>
<p id="6.1">
<title>Knowledge base</title>
<text_body>
<itemize>
<item>Appendix A: Glossary</item>
<item>Appendix B: Analysis Models. Optionally, include any pertinent analysis models, such as data flow
diagrams, class diagrams, state-transition diagrams, or entity-relationship
diagrams.</item>
<item>Appendix C: Issues List. This is a dynamic list of the open requirements issues that remain to be
resolved, including TBDs, pending decisions, information that is needed,
conflicts awaiting resolution, and the like.</item>
</itemize>
</text_body>
</p>
</p>
</req_document>