<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- New document created with EditiX at Tue Jun 07 14:21:44 CEST 2011 -->
<req_document  xsi:schemaLocation="req_document.xsd req_document.xsd"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xmlns="req_document.xsd">

<title>
  Software Requirements
  Specification
  for
  Internetworking of
  Content Delivery Networks
  through Peering
</title>
<version>0.1</version>
<issue_date>2010-03-08</issue_date>

<p id="1">
  <title>Introduction</title>
  <p id="1.1">
    <title>Purpose</title>
    <text_body>
      This document describes the requirements specification (SRS) for the software infrastructure (or
      product) that enables the internetworking of Content Delivery Networks (CDNs) through peering,
      henceforth termed as ‘CDN peering’, and provides an overall description of it. It presents a means for
      distinct CDNs to coordinate and cooperate with other CDNs, by investigating and developing (a)
      models for effective internetworking between CDNs though peering; (b) protocols for service
      delivery in a cooperative environment of CDNs; (c) some concrete examples (technology trends) that
      exhibits the notion of content networking; and (d) policies for autonomic management of service level
      through resource negotiation in an on-demand basis. Thus, this document provides a basis for
      evaluating the proposal for internetworking between CDNs. This is the version 0.1 of the software
      requirements specification.
    </text_body>
  </p>
  <p id="1.2">
    <title>Document Conventions and Terminology</title>
    <text_body>
      When writing this SRS for CDN peering, the following terminologies are used:
      <itemize>
        <item>Web server (WS): The container of content comprising of two layersoverlay, which is a collection of Web service host (e.g. Apache, Tomcat), Service Level Agreement (SLA)- allocator, and policy agent, and core, which refers to the underlying hardware infrastructure.</item>
        <item>Mediator: A policy-driven entity, authoritative for policy negotiation and management.</item>
        <item>Service registry (SR): Discovers and stores resource and policy information in local domain.</item>
        <item>Peering Agent (PA): A resource discovery module in the peering CDNs environment.</item>
        <item>Policy repository (PR): A storage of Web server, mediator and peering policies.</item>
        <item>PWS: A set of Web server-specific rules for content storage and management.</item>
        <item>PM: A set of mediator-specific rules for interaction and negotiation.</item>
        <item>PPeering: A set of rules for creation and growth of the peering arrangement.</item>
      </itemize>
    </text_body>
  </p>
  <p id="1.3">
    <title>Intended Audience and Reading Suggestions</title>
    <text_body>
      This document is written for the researchers, software developers, advanced practitioners,
      documentation writers, and users involved in CDN domain to initiation an open discussion for
      exploring development opportunities regarding the internetworking between CDNs. Section 2
      discusses the steps that are to be undertaken to “bring-up” or “cease” an internetworking arrangement
      between CDNs. In the next section, system features with their functional requirements are presented
      to highlight the major services provided by the intended product. Then the external interface
      requirements highlighting the logical characteristics of each interface between the software product
      and the users are discussed. Finally, this specification is concluded with the reference documents on
      which this document is based on.
    </text_body>
  </p>
  <p id="1.4">
    <title>Project Scope</title>
    <text_body>
      The final product enabling CDN peering assists in coordinated and cooperative content delivery via
      internetworking among distinct CDNs to allow providers to rapidly “scale-out” to meet both flash
      crowds and anticipated increases in demand, and remove the need for a single CDN to provision
      resources. An ad-hoc or planned peering of CDNs requires fundamental research to be undertaken to
      address the core problems of measuring and disseminating load information, performing request
      assignment and redirection, enabling content replication and determining appropriate compensation
      among participants on a geographically distributed “Internet” scale. In contrast to a single CDN, for
      which these issues are deeply interrelated and co-dependent, the main thrust for the final product
      enabling CDN peering is to consider them in a coordinated and cooperative manner among many
      peered CDNs, whilst satisfying the complex multi-dimensional constraints placed on each individual
      provider. Each provider must ensure that their individual SLAs are met when serving content for its
      own customers to end users, while meeting any obligations it has made when participating in a group
      of many providers.
    </text_body>
  </p>
  <p id="1.5">
    <title>References</title>
    <text_body>
      This document builds on the following references:
      <itemize>
        <item>An introduction to CDN technologies [1].</item>
        <item>The research problem for internetworking of CDNs [2]</item>
        <item>The architecture for CDN peering [3].</item>
        <item>The performance models to demonstrate the effects of peering and to predict user perceived performance [4].</item> 
        <item>CDN peering models along with the challenges for implementation [5].</item>
      </itemize>
    </text_body>
  </p>
</p>
<p id="2">
  <title>Overall Description</title>
  <p id="2.1">
    <title>Product Perspective</title>
    <text_body>
      CDN peering allows different CDN providers to share resources in order to provide larger scale
      and/or reach to each participant than they could not achieve otherwise. It is formed by a set of
      autonomous CDNs, which cooperate through a mechanism that provides facilities and infrastructure
      for cooperation in order to virtualize multiple providers. It is expected that an effective peering
      arrangement between CDNs would require multiple steps to occur.
      <itemize>
        <item>Initiation: A CDN’s reach and scale is limited by its ability to handle peak load, cost of equipment, scalable infrastructure, and/or demand for the increased coverage of its infrastructure. Peering allows a particular CDN to achieve larger scale/reach through resource sharing with other CDN(s). It is triggered by an initialization request sent to the mediator under exceptional circumstances, e.g. flash crowds, when the (primary) CDN realizes that it cannot handle a part of the workload on its Web Servers (WSs). The triggering condition must consider the expected and unexpected load increases in the initiating CDN.</item>
        <item>Negotiated relationship: The controlling interest of a CDN to interconnect with other CDNs leads to the creation of a negotiated relationship. In the business domain, this relationship (most likely) would take the form of a legal document which describes the expected level of services from the involving parties such as storage requirements, the required rate of transfer, cost of services; the expected duration of receiving service, penalties for service violations, and other preconditions such as the initiating CDN’s preference to gain resources at a particular region. Negotiated relationships can also be established through means nontechnical terms (financial statement) or technical terms (SLAs). Thus, negotiated relationships must specify the interactions among entities including service administration, coordination and disband (or re-arrangement) of internetworked CDNs. In the CDN peering architecture, the mediator instance obtains the resource and access information from the Service Registry (SR), whilst SLAs and other policies from the Policy Repository (PR). The mediator instance on the primary CDN’s behalf generates its service requirements based on the current circumstance and SLA requirements of its customer(s). Therefore, divergent policies are allowed that specify the information that can be shared during interaction through providing a certain level of visibility to preserve privacy.</item>
        <item>Resource discovery: Once the initiating CDN identifies its roles and activities through the created negotiated relationships for coordination and cooperation between CDNs, the next step is to choose potential CDNs to peer with. The mediator instance passes the service requirements to the local PA to discover external resources from peers. The PA performs the resource discovery process through predicting performance of the peers, working around issues of separate administration and limited information sharing among enlisted CDNs. If there are any preexisting peering arrangements (for a long term scenario) then these will be returned at this point. Otherwise, it carries out short term negotiations with the Peering Agent (PA) identified peering targets.</item>
        <item>CDN peering protocols: The next step is to configure the ‘CDN peering’ protocols at the conduit of the respective CDNs in order to technically support the terms and policies implicitly specified through the negotiated relationships. This step includes advertising the configurations (topology aspects, geographical proximity, capability, performance, etc.) of enlisted CDNs through inter-PA communication. On establishment of a peering arrangement, these protocols also allow participating CDNs to exchange information regarding the content availability and assists to redirect requests to an optimal peer. Request-redirection in a peering arrangement depends on the content distribution and request-routing policies (specified in the CDN peering protocols) associated with the content as well as the specific algorithms and methods used for directing these requests.</item>
        <item>Operational management: When the primary CDN acquires sufficient resources from the peers to meet its SLA with the customer, the new peering arrangement becomes operational. Hence, necessary functional policies are deployed and administered in an effective way. Once a peering arrangement is established, all participating parties cooperate in the execution of common goal(s). Peering also enables the CDNs to exchange accounting information to perform billing based on the negotiated relationships. If no CDN is interested in such peering, peering arrangement creation through re-negotiation is resumed by tuning the negotiated relationships with reconsidered service requirements.</item>
        <item>Disband or re-arrangement: An existing peering arrangement may need to either disband or re-arrange itself (within the scope of the negotiated relationships) if any of the following conditions hold: (a) the circumstances under which the arrangement was formed no longer hold; (b) peering is no longer beneficial for the participating CDNs; (c) an existing peering arrangement needs to be expanded further in order to deal with additional load; or (d) participating CDNs are not meeting their agreed upon contributions.</item>
      </itemize>
      Figure 1 presents the interaction flows within the architecture of the CDN peering with an abstraction on its components.
    </text_body>
    <p id="Figure 1"></p>
  </p>
  <p id="2.2">
    <title>Product Features</title>
    <text_body>
      The software infrastructure enabling peering between CDNs can be featured with the following major
      goals:
      <itemize>
        <item>Development and validation of peering and manage the complexity of content delivery across Web servers of multiple CDNs that scale across the globe.</item>
        <item>Decrease cost of Web access, increase QoS through reduced latency, reduce server load, and bandwidth consumption (by a particular CDN server), thus improving the performance of content delivery.</item>
        <item>Assists an existing CDN to alleviate congestions by detecting and handling short-term load spikes (i.e. flash crowds) effectively.</item>
      </itemize>
      The operations performed by the product components [3] assist to realize the above goals.
      Component-wise major functions are noted below.
      The functions of the Web server(s) and its constituents are as follows,
      <itemize>
        <item>A Web server replicates content on-demand from the origin server and stores it for future use.</item>
        <item>In the event of Web hotspot, it initiates request to trigger peering.</item>
        <item>The Web services host ensures the delivery of content to end-users based on the negotiated policies with other CDNs.</item>
        <item>The policy agent is responsible (in conjunction with the mediator) for determining which resources can be delegated and under what conditions (policies) delegation is permitted.</item>
        <item>The SLA-allocator performs the provisioning and reservation of Web server’s resources (e.g. CPU, bandwidth, storage etc.) to satisfy both local and delegated SLAs, and ensures that the terms of the SLAs are enforced.</item>
        <item>The Web servers’ underlying algorithms perform on-demand caching, content selection, and routing between servers.</item>
      </itemize>
      The Mediator performs the following major functions,
      <itemize>
        <item>It generates service requirements as the basis for negotiated relationships.</item>
        <item>It passes the service requirements to the PA.</item>
        <item>It works in conjunction with its local PA to discover external resources and to negotiate with other CDNs.</item>
        <item>Once a peering arrangement is established, it controls what portion of the Web traffic (i.e. end-user requests) is redirected to the Web servers of the peering CDNs, which content is replicated there, how the replication decision is taken, and which replication policies are being used.</item>
        <item>It ensures that the participating entities are able to adapt to changing circumstances (agility) and are able to achieve their objectives in a dynamic and uncertain environment (resilience)</item>
      </itemize>
      The main functions of the Service Registry are as follows,
      <itemize>
        <item>It encapsulates the resource and service information for each CDN.</item>
        <item>It helps in discovering local resources through enabling the Web servers of CDN providers to register and publish their resource, service and policy details.</item>
        <item>In the face of traffic surges, it supplies any necessary local resource information to the mediator.</item>
        <item>When a new peering arrangement is established, an instance of the service registry is created that encapsulates all local and delegated external CDN resources.</item>
      </itemize>
      The Policy Repository is used to perform the following functions,
      <itemize>
        <item>It virtualizes all of the policies within a peering arrangement including PWS, PM, and PPeering (i.e. Web server-specific policies, mediator policies, peering policies), along with any delegated policies for resources as a result of the peering arrangement.</item>
        <item>It provides a set of rules to the mediator to administer, manage, and control access to the resources in a peering arrangement.</item>
        <item>It returns existing peering policies to the PA during the establishment of long-term peering arrangements.</item>
      </itemize>
      A Peering Agent carries out the following major functions,
      <itemize>
        <item>It acts as a policy-driven resource discovery module for establishing negotiations.</item>
        <item>It exchanges policy, resource information, and service requirements with external PAs.</item>
        <item>It is used as a conduit by the mediator to establish negotiations with PAs of other peers and to acquire resources from them.</item>
      </itemize>
      The operations performed by the components of the CDN peering is driven by semi-autonomous logic
      that ensures content is served reliably through content replication, request-routing and redirection
      whilst maintaining constant awareness of the health (e.g. load information) of participants. These
      major architectural features of the CDN peering are briefly described in the following:
      <itemize>
        <item>Content replication is performed using a cooperative pull-based approach where participating CDNs assist each others in serving data. Thus, content replication is featured through extending it to participating servers from the peers in a given peering arrangement, subject to the available resources they contribute</item>
        <item>Load distribution is performed by measuring the load information and disseminating it within individual CDNs and amongst other CDNs using a hierarchical approach, where current bandwidth and resource usage of web servers in a CDN is reported to the CDN gateway (i.e. mediator, PA and policy repository as a single conceptual entity) in a periodic or thresholdbased manner. The gateways of participating CDNs then communicate aggregated load information describing the load of their constituent servers.</item>
        <item>Request assignment and redirection is performed at multiple levels – at the DNS, at the gateways to local clusters, and also (redirection) between servers in a cluster. Therefore, endusers can be assigned via DNS (by the peering agents of participating CDNs updating their DNS records regularly) and also via redirection at the CDN gateway when appropriate.</item>
      </itemize>
    </text_body>
  </p>
  <p id="2.3">
    <title>User Classes and Characteristics</title>
    <text_body>
      The users of the software infrastructure enabling CDN peering can be differentiated by using their
      membership and contributions to the system. A given peering arrangement consists of explicit and
      implicit members. Explicit members include the primary CDN, which is the initiator of a peering
      relationship, and any peering CDNs who cooperate for resource sharing. Implicit members are content
      providers and end-users. Implicit members are transparent to a peering arrangement but they share the
      benefit from it. In addition, users can vary based on the purpose, size, scope and duration of peering.
      For instance, a short-term peering arrangement is to be automated to react within a tight time
      frameas it is unlikely that a human directed negotiation would occur quickly enough to satisfy the
      evolved niche. On the other hand, establishment of a long-term peering arrangement calls for a
      human-directed agent to ensure that any resulting decisions comply with participating CDNs’
      strategic goals. Users can also be classified because of the preferential treatment that they may receive
      due to the policy that pertains to a particular provider’s business logic. Moreover, individual users (or
      a group of users) can have dynamic QoS requirements depending on the situations that will result in
      “customized” content delivery. Thus, users (or class of users) can be differentiated based on userdefined
      QoS specifications while accessing the service.
    </text_body>
  </p>
  <p id="2.4">
    <title>Operating Environment</title>
    <text_body>
      The product (i.e. prototype system) enabling CDN peering is expected to be deployed it in a realworld
      test bed such as PlanetLab for global testing, observations, and for performance evaluation. In
      this regard, existing Web services technologies will be studied in detail to examine the feasibility of
      leveraging them. A modular implementation stack could be developed on top of the existing standard
      application layer (e.g. Apache, Tomcat) and protocols (e.g. HTTP, CDI, HTPC). A modular
      implementation approach would be useful to perform testing on modules at different stages to ensure
      correct implementation. It is anticipated that a cryptographically secure auction-based framework will
      be used to assist content replication among peered CDNs to allow incentives for all participants. Load
      information could be measured and disseminated within individual CDNs and among other CDNs
      using distributed load indices such as Distributed Hash Table (DHT) or variations of it. Request
      assignment and redirection could predominantly rely on DNS-level end-user assignment combined
      with a rudimentary request assignment policy such as weighted round-robin or least-loaded-first,
      which updates the DNS records to point to the most appropriate replica server of the peers.
    </text_body>
  </p>
  <p id="2.5">
    <title>Design and Implementation Constraints</title>
    <text_body>
      The challenges in developing the product include virtualization of multiple providers and offloading
      end-user requests from the primary CDN provider to peers based on cost, performance and load. Due
      to the proprietary nature of existing CDNs, limited information about response time or service cost is
      typically available from individual CDNs, and load balancing control is retained by an individual
      provider within its own Web servers. Therefore, request-redirections must occur over distributed sets
      of Web servers belonging to multiple CDN providers, without the benefit of the full information
      available, as in the single provider case. Moreover, an implementation model for the product enabling
      CDN peering could be based on a complex combination of attributes such as Web server
      responsiveness or load, expected network delay, or geographic location. Several of these potential
      attributes vary over time and there is no single repository for listing the value of attributes such as
      geographic location or expected delay for all Internet-connected systems. It is anticipated that the
      values used in a CDN peering implementation model are likely to be based on heuristics.
    </text_body>
  </p>
  <p id="2.6">
    <title>User Documentation</title>
    <text_body>
      Along with the software product, a user manual would be written to help people understand the
      working methodology and usage of the developed prototype system. It would be written for nontechnical
      individuals and the level of content or terminology would differ considerably from, for
      example, a System Administration Guide, which is more detailed and complex. The user manual
      would follow common user documentation styles capturing purpose and scope of the product along
      with key system features and operations; step-by-step instructions for using the system including
      conventions, messaging structures, quick references, tips for errors and malfunctions; pointers to
      reference documents; and glossary of terms.
    </text_body>
  </p>
  <p id="2.7">
    <title>Assumptions and Dependencies</title>
    <text_body>
      The product would build on leveraging existing systems. In this regard, necessary inspirations could
      be obtained by analyzing related systems such as CoDeeN, Coral, Globule, and MotusNet. In
      particular, the design and implementation approach of MotusNet could be helpful to draw a clear
      guideline for developing the intended prototype.
    </text_body>
  </p>
</p>
<p id="3">
    <title>System Features</title>
    <text_body>
      The major services and functional requirements for the product can be illustrated by system features.
      This section is organized by use cases for major system features. In the following, necessary
      description is provided for each use cases in the system. Each use case description provides
      information of the associated actors, triggering condition, preconditions, postconditions, response
      sequences, exceptions and functional requirements (assumptions). Being a major important section of
      the SRS, this section is expected to go through iterative improvement to make the most logical sense
      for the intended product.
    </text_body>
    <p id="3.1">
      <title>Service Registration</title>
      <text_body>
        This feature is associated with the registration of resource and service information of each CDN to its
        SR. The use case for this feature is shown in Figure 2.
      </text_body>
      <p id="Figure 2"></p>
      <p id="3.1.1">
        <title>Actors</title>
        <text_body>
          WS: Publishes its resource and service information to the SR.
          SR: Registers available local resources at the CDN provider and updates them.
          Mediator: Collects up-to-date resource information from SR.
        </text_body>
      </p>
      <p id="3.1.2">
        <title>Trigger</title>
        <text_body>
          Service registration is triggered when either one of the following occurs: (a) resources
          are available as a provider starts operating; (b) previously registered resource
          information needs to be updated; (c) available local resource information is required in
          the event of traffic surges; and (d) local and delegated external resource information is
          to be encapsulated in an SR instance included in an established peering arrangement.
        </text_body>
      </p>
      <p id="3.1.3">
        <title>Preconditions</title>
        <text_body>
          Available local resources of a CDN provider are detected along with their service
          information such as CPU, storage, upload and download rate, etc. These resources
          could be provisioned and reserved to satisfy SLAs.
        </text_body>
      </p>
      <p id="3.1.4">
        <title>Postconditions</title>
        <text_body>
          Resources are registered in the service registry and being updated in a regular basis.
        </text_body>
      </p>
      <p id="3.1.5">
        <title>Stimulus/Response Sequences</title>
        <text_body>
          <itemize>
            <item>Each CDN Web server publishes resource and service information.</item>
            <item>If it is a new resource, its service information is registered in the SR with a new resource ID. Resource ID counter is incremented.</item>
            <item>Else, resource information in SR is updated in a regular basis.</item>
            <item>In the face of traffic surges, information on available local resources along withtheir IDs is supplied to the Mediator.</item>
            <item>Local and delegated external resource information is encapsulated in the SR instance in the established peering arrangement.</item>
          </itemize>
        </text_body>
      </p>
      <p id="3.1.6">
        <title>Exceptions</title>
        <text_body>
          If a resource fails, its service information is removed from SR and the resource ID counter is decremented.
        </text_body>
      </p>
      <p id="3.1.7">
        <title>Functional Requirements</title>
        <req id="1">
          <text_body>
            The format for service information description is defined
          </text_body>
        </req>
        <req id="1">
          <text_body>
            The format for service information description is defined
          </text_body>
        </req>
        <req id="2">
          <text_body>
            The interaction protocol between Web Server-SR, SR-mediator is defined.
          </text_body>
        </req>
        <req id="3">
          <text_body>
            Resource provisioning, delegation and reservation policies are in place
          </text_body>
        </req>
        <req id="4">
          <text_body>
            There is an established norm that any resource failure will be reported
          </text_body>
        </req>
        <req id="5">
          <text_body>
            The interaction protocol between Web Server-SR, SR-mediator is defined.
          </text_body>
        </req>
      </p>
    </p>
    <p id="3.2">
      <title>Request Initiation to Trigger Peering</title>
      <text_body>
        This feature relates to the initialization of peering between CDNs. The use case for this feature is
        shown in Figure 3.
      </text_body>
      <p id="Figure 3"></p>

      <p id="3.2.1">
        <title>Actors</title>
        <text_body>
          End-user: Requests for content.
          Mediator: Receives initiation request from WS to trigger peering.
        </text_body>
      </p>
      <p id="3.2.2">
        <title>Trigger</title>
        <text_body>
          It is invoked when a (primary) CDN realizes that it cannot handle a part of the
          workload on its WS(s). The triggering condition considers the expected and
          unexpected load increases in the initiating (primary) CDN.
        </text_body>
      </p>
      <p id="3.2.3">
        <title>Preconditions</title>
        <text_body>
          Exceptional circumstances such as flash crowds have occurred to place unanticipated
          load on CDN WSs.
        </text_body>
      </p>
      <p id="3.2.4">
        <title>Postconditions</title>
        <text_body>
          An initialization request is sent to the mediator to trigger peering.
        </text_body>
      </p>
      <p id="3.2.5">
        <title>Actors</title>
        <text_body>
          <itemize>
            <item>End users request for content from CDN WSs.</item>
            <item>Flash crowds occurred due to a sudden burst in traffic.</item>
            <item>Flash crowds occurred due to a sudden burst in traffic.</item>
            <item>Flash crowds occurred due to a sudden burst in traffic.</item>
          </itemize>
        </text_body>
      </p>
      <p id="3.2.6">
        <title>Exceptions</title>
        <text_body>
          If the user requests experience service timeout (threshold), initiation request is
          cancelled.
        </text_body>
      </p>
      <p id="3.2.7">
        <title>Exceptions</title>
        <req id="1">
          <text_body>
            Malicious requests are detected and rejected.
          </text_body>
        </req>
        <req id="2">
          <text_body>
            Web servers have already replicated necessary content.
          </text_body>
        </req>
        <req id="3">
          <text_body>
            Both anticipated and unanticipated user requests (traffic) are considered.
          </text_body>
        </req>
        <req id="4">
          <text_body>
            The format for service information description is defined
          </text_body>
        </req>
      </p>
    </p>
    <p id="3.3">
      <title>Mediator Invokes Creation of Negotiated Relationship</title>
      <text_body>
        On receipt of the initialization request to trigger peering, the mediator of the primary CDN invokes
        negotiation. Figure 4 shows use case for this feature.
      </text_body>
      <p id="Figure 4"></p>

      <p id="3.3.1">
        <title>Actors</title>
        <text_body>
          SR: Sends resource and access information.
          PR: Sends policy information for establishing negotiated relationships
          PA: Receives service requirements from the mediator.
        </text_body>
      </p>
      <p id="3.3.2">
        <title>Trigger</title>
        <text_body>
          Upon receiving the initialization request to trigger peering, the mediator generates
          service requirements and passes it to local PA.
        </text_body>
      </p>
      <p id="3.3.3">
        <title>Preconditions</title>
        <text_body>
          Initialization request is received.
        </text_body>
      </p>
      <p id="3.3.4">
        <title>Postconditions</title>
        <text_body>
          Service requirements are generated and they are sent to the local PA.
        </text_body>
      </p>
      <p id="3.3.5">
        <title>Stimulus/Response Sequences</title>
        <text_body>
          <itemize>
            <item>An initialization request to activate peering is received by the mediator.</item>
            <item>The mediator instance obtains resource and access information from the SR and policy information from PR to establish negotiation.</item>
            <item>The mediator generates service requirements.</item>
            <item>If the service requirements are acceptable according to the provider’s policy, mediator passes it to the local PA.</item>
            <item>Else, reject user requests.</item>
          </itemize>
        </text_body>
      </p>
      <p id="3.3.6">
        <title>Exceptions</title>
        <text_body>
          If the user requests can not be accepted according the provider policies, service
          requirements are not passed to the local PA.
        </text_body>
      </p>
      <p id="3.3.7">
        <title>Exceptions</title>
        <req id="1">
          <text_body>
            The format of service requirements is defined.
          </text_body>
        </req>
        <req id="2">
          <text_body>
            Mediator-SR, mediator-PR, mediator-PA interaction protocols are defined.
          </text_body>
        </req>
        <req id="3">
          <text_body>
            Mediator works in conjunction with the PA to establish negotiation.
          </text_body>
        </req>
      </p>
    </p>
    <p id="3.4">
      <title>Resource Discovery through PA</title>
      <text_body>
        The PA of a given primary CDN negotiates with PAs of the peers to perform external resource
        discovery. Figure 5 shows the use case related to this feature.
      </text_body>

      <p id="3.4.1">
        <title>Actors</title>
        <text_body>
          External PA: Negotiates with the PA of the primary CDN.
          PR: Receives negotiated policies from the local PA.
        </text_body>
      </p>
      <p id="3.4.2">
        <title>Trigger</title>
        <text_body>
          Local PA communicates with the PAs of peers to discover external resources.
        </text_body>
      </p>
      <p id="3.4.3">
        <title>Preconditions</title>
        <text_body>
          Service requirements are received from the mediator.
        </text_body>
      </p>
      <p id="3.4.4">
        <title>Postconditions</title>
        <text_body>
          Negotiation is performed and a peering arrangement is established through inter-PA communications.
        </text_body>
      </p>
      <p id="3.4.5">
        <title>Stimulus/Response Sequences</title>
        <text_body>
          <itemize>
            <item>Local PA receives service requirements from the mediator.</item>
            <item>If any peering policies exist, they are returned to establish long-term peering arrangement.</item>
            <item>Else, short-term negotiation is performed.</item>
            <item>Local PA in conjunction with the mediator interacts with external PAs through inter-PA communication protocol.</item>
            <item>External resources are discovered and negotiation is performed with selected CDN peers.</item>
            <item>If sufficient resources are acquired, a peering arrangement is established</item>
            <item>Else, mediator re-evaluates service requirements and sends to the local PA to perform re-negotiation.</item>
          </itemize>
        </text_body>
      </p>
      <p id="Figure 5"></p>
      <p id="3.4.6">
        <title>Exceptions</title>
        <text_body>
          If the user requests can not be accepted according the provider policies, service
          requirements are not passed to the local PA.
        </text_body>
      </p>
      <p id="3.4.7">
        <title>Exceptions</title>
        <req id="1">
          <text_body>
            Interaction protocols between PAs are identified.
          </text_body>
        </req>
        <req id="2">
          <text_body>
            Malicious requests are identified and acted upon.
          </text_body>
        </req>
        <req id="3">
          <text_body>
            There are existing policies for long-term peering arrangement.
          </text_body>
        </req>
        <req id="4">
          <text_body>
            There is procedure to perform short-term negotiation.
          </text_body>
        </req>
      </p>
    </p>
    <p id="3.5">
      <title>Operational Management</title>
      <text_body>
        This feature is responsible for the inter-CDN protocol configuration, resource initialization and for
        ensuring effective operations of the established peering arrangement. The use case for this feature is
        shown in Figure 6.
      </text_body>
      <p id="Figure 6">

        <p id="3.5.1">
          <title>Actors</title>
          <text_body>
            External PA: Exchanges configurations and content availability information, and
            accepts requests to an optimal peer.
            PR: Assists in enforcing negotiated policies.
          </text_body>
        </p>
        <p id="3.5.2">
          <title>Trigger</title>
          <text_body>
            Once policies are negotiated and a peering arrangement is established, PAs interact
            each other in the execution of common goal(s).
          </text_body>
        </p>
        <p id="3.5.3">
          <title>Preconditions</title>
          <text_body>
            A peering arrangement is established.
          </text_body>
        </p>
        <p id="3.5.4">
          <title>Postconditions</title>
          <text_body>
            Necessary functions policies are deployed and administration for effective operations.
          </text_body>
        </p>
        <p id="3.5.5">
          <title>Stimulus/Response Sequences</title>
          <text_body>
            <itemize>
              <item>Once a peering arrangement is established, the initiating primary CDN through its local PA advertise configuration information to technically support the negotiated relationships between enlisted CDNs.</item>
              <item>PAs exchange content availability and load information to identify an optimal peer to handle user requests.</item>
              <item>Request is redirected to an optimal peer’s Web server.</item>
              <item>PAs exchange accounting information to perform billing based on negotiated relationships.</item>
              <item>The policy repository instance in the established peering arrangement assists in the deployment, administration and enforcement of the functional policies.</item>
            </itemize>
          </text_body>
        </p>
        <p id="3.5.6">
          <title>Exceptions</title>
          <text_body>
            If a peered CDN provider refuses to accept user requests, a given peering arrangement
            ceases.
          </text_body>
        </p>
        <p id="3.5.7">
          <title>Exceptions</title>
          <req id="1">
            <text_body>
              Negotiation is established between selected CDN peers.
            </text_body>
          </req>
          <req id="2">
            <text_body>
              Primary CDN has already acquired sufficient external resources.
            </text_body>
          </req>
          <req id="3">
            <text_body>
              Functional policies are identified and deployed.
            </text_body>
          </req>
          <req id="4">
            <text_body>
              Effective content delivery is ensured through SLA satisfaction.
            </text_body>
          </req>
        </p>
      </p>
    </p>
    <p id="3.6">
      <title>Disband or Re-arrangement</title>
      <text_body>
        There could be circumstances under which a given peering arrangement may need to disband or rearranges
        itself. This feature is associated with the use case shown in Figure 7.
      </text_body>

      <p id="3.6.1">
        <title>Actors</title>
        <text_body>
          External PA: Interactions with local PA of the primary CDN.
        </text_body>
      </p>
      <p id="3.6.2">
        <title>Trigger</title>
        <text_body>
          Any of the termination condition holds.
        </text_body>
      </p>
      <p id="3.6.3">
        <title>Preconditions</title>
        <text_body>
          There is an established peering arrangement.
        </text_body>
      </p>
      <p id="3.6.4">
        <title>Postconditions</title>
        <text_body>
          A given peering arrangement is disband or it is re-arranged.
        </text_body>
      </p>
      <p id="3.6.5">
        <title>Stimulus/Response Sequences</title>
        <text_body>
          <itemize>
            <item>A given peering arrangement is currently in operation and peers are cooperating for effective content delivery.</item>
            <item>If any of the termination condition holds, the local PA disbands or re-arranges the peering arrangement.</item>
          </itemize>
        </text_body>
      </p>
      <p id="Figure 7"></p>
      <p id="3.6.6">
        <title>Exceptions</title>
        <text_body>
          If there are exceptional circumstances such as natural disaster, theft, etc. for which any peer is unable to honor the negotiated relationships, a given peering arrangement is not disband or re-arranged and SLA conditions are bypassed.
        </text_body>
      </p>
      <p id="3.6.7">
        <title>Exceptions</title>
        <req id="1">
          <text_body>
            Policies identifying the consequences of SLA violation are defined.
          </text_body>
        </req>
        <req id="2">
          <text_body>
            Policies are in place to perform renegotiation for problem resolution.
          </text_body>
        </req>
        <req id="3">
          <text_body>
            Policies are in place to perform renegotiation for problem resolution.
          </text_body>
        </req>
      </p>
    </p>
</p>
<p id="4">
  <title>External Interface Requirements</title>
  <p id="4.1">
  <title>User Interfaces</title>
  <text_body>
    This section describes the logical characteristics of each interface between the intended software
    product and the users. For user interface design, common GUI standards will be followed along with
    the presence of keyboard shortcuts, error message display standards etc., and standard buttons and
    functions (i.e. help) will appear on every screen. Details of the user interface design are intended to be
    documented in a separate user interface specification.
  </text_body>
</p>
  <p id="4.2">
    <title>Communications Interfaces</title>
    <text_body>
      As mentioned earlier, the intended product to exploit existing Web service technologies to leverage
      existing infrastructures through building an overlay. The communication among software component
      would be performed through message passing over the IP network. From a technical point of view,
      TCP/IP will be used as the transport protocol, where each CDN server establishes a TCP connection
      to the network elements using a well-known port number. Messages can then be sent bi-directionally
      between the server and network elements. All messages consist of a fixed length-header containing
      the total data length and a request followed by a reply or an acknowledgement. Interaction among
      surrogates will be performed using HTTP or FTP.
    </text_body>
  </p>
</p>
<p id="5">
  <title>References</title>
  <text_body>
    <itemize>
      <item>Pathan, M., Buyya, R., Vakali, A. CDNs: State of the Art, Insights, and Imperatives. Content Delivery Networks. Buyya, R., Pathan, M., and Vakali, A. (eds.), Springer-Verlag, Germany, Mar. 2008.</item>
      <item>Buyya, R., Pathan, M., Broberg, J., and Tari, Z. A Case for Peering of Content Delivery Networks, IEEE Distributed Systems Online, 7(10), USA, Oct. 2006.</item>
      <item>Pathan, M., Bubendorfer, K., Kim, K. H., and An Architecture for Virtual Organization (VO)-Based Effective Peering of Content Delivery Networks, UPGRADE-CN’07, In Proc. of the 16th IEEE International Symposium on High Performance Distributed Computing (HPDC), USA, Jun. 2007.</item>
      <item>Pathan, M., Broberg, J., and Buyya, R. An Approach for QoS-Aware Performance Modeling of Peering Content Delivery Networks. Technical Report, GRIDS-TR-2007-19, Grid Computing and Distributed Systems Laboratory, University of Melbourne, Australia, Oct. 2007.</item>
      <item>Pathan, M., Buyya, R., Broberg, J. Internetworking of CDNs. Content Delivery Networks. Buyya, R., Pathan, M., and Vakali, A. (eds.), Springer-Verlag, Germany, Mar. 2008.</item>
    </itemize>
  </text_body>
</p>
</req_document> 